Daniel Krastev Computer Science Graduate

Studying and working towards getting a first class degree at the University of Kent allowed me to acquire valuable experience in a variety of computer science fields, including Mobile Development, IoT, Machine Learning, Web Development and Cybersecurity. Doing projects in these areas helped me develop strong logical thinking and a positive attitude towards difficult problems. Using these problem-solving skills as a foundation, I am very motivated to further expand my knowledge and build a successful career.

danielkrastev@hotmail.com (+44)7 424 124 821

Royal Tunbridge Wells, UK in linkedin.com/in/daniel-krastev

didko0 github.com/daniel-krastev

EDUCATION

BSc Computer Science with a Year in Industry University of Kent, Canterbury (UK)

09/2015 - Present

Courses

- · Stage 1, Final Mark: Distinction (86%)
- Stage 2, Final Mark: Distinction (80%)
- Placement Year, Software Developer / Internship at IdeaWorks Ltd., Final Mark: (81%)
- Final Year: Internet of Things (78%); Cognitive Neural Networks; Computer Security and Cryptography; Introduction to Intelligent Systems; Data Mining; Computational Creativity.

BSc Navigational Engineer

"Nikola Vaptsarov" Naval Academy, Varna (Bulgaria)

09/2008 - 05/2012

High School Diploma (5,77/6.00)

"Atanas Radev" School of Mathematics, Yambol (Bulgaria)

09/2004 - 05/2008

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer - Internship

IdeaWorks Ltd., Faversham (UK)

07/2017 - 07/2018

Tasks

- Adding new features to Android/Java products and C++ libraries.
- Fixing bugs for Android/Java products.
- · Working with Dart and Flutter SDK on a future iteration of a flagship product of the company.
- Using Selenium for web testing.
- Using XML with Android projects for configuration and validation.
- Rooting, flashing Android phones/tablets.
- Producing and testing Crestron hooking templates.
- Extensively working with Git version control.
- Working with other team members on pairs-testing and joint development.

Ship's Deck Officer Stamco Ship Management

05/2012 - 04/2015

Tasks

- Navigating the ship 8 hours per day.
- Maintaining the safety equipment on board (lifeboats, life rafts, fire extinguishers, etc.)

PROJECTS

Wobble Board (2019)

• A mobile application that communicates with a microcontroller over BLE. The microcontroller sits inside a wobble board and sends orientation data to the application. The application uses that data in its three modes: Recovery, Exercise, Game. Technologies: Arduino, BLE, Dart, Flutter.

Mobile Application: github.com/daniel-krastev/wobble_board_app Microcontroller: github.com/daniel-krastev/wobble_nRF52-DK_arduino

EvoComposer (2019)

• This is an implementation of a genetic algorithm that composes music based on a set of "guiding" songs. Technologies: Java, Genetic Algorithms.

Application: github.com/daniel-krastev/evo_composer

River Levels (2018)

• A web application that consumes data about the level of the Great River Stour in Canterbury provided by a number of sensors and presents that in a useful manner to the user. Technologies: React.js, Node.js, MySQL, LeafletJS. Web Application: github.com/daniel-krastev/river-levels

Earthquakes (2018)

• A mobile application that fetches data about the earthquakes around the world and displays that to the user in the form of a list. Technologies: Dart, Flutter, REST API.

Mobile Application: github.com/daniel-krastev/earthquakes

Photographic Memory Puzzle (2017)

 $\bullet \ \, \text{This is a desktop version of the famous pairs matching game. Technologies: Java, Swing API.}$

Desktop Application: github.com/daniel-krastev/memory_game

Blog (2017)

• A simple micro-blogging web page that allows the users to log in, post messages, follow other users, search for messages, view a combined feed of messages posted by everybody they follow. Technologies: PHP, Codelgniter, MVC. Blog: github.com/daniel-krastev/blog-codeigniter

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages

• Java (Android, Selenium, JNI, JUnit); Dart (Flutter); C/C++ (IoT); HTML/CSS; XML; JavaScript (React.js); PHP (CodeIgniter); Erlang; SQL.

Tools & Technologies

• Git; Object Oriented Programming (OOP); Using REST APIs; Firebase; MVC; Linux; IntelliJ IDEA; NetBeans; Atom.

Courses

Java - Multithreading (Udemy.com); Flutter/Dart (Udemy.com); Git (Udemy.com); Codelgniter (Udemy.com).

REFERENCES

Available on request.